ILGWU. Carl Proper papers 5780/150
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Kurt Salmon Associates (KSA): Marketing and Technology Study, 1990-1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  Report, "Keeping New York in Fashion," 1992, prepared for GIDC by Kurt Salmon Associates (KSA); agenda for meeting describing project, June 13, 1990; Request for Proposals, Women's and Children's Apparel Marketing and Technology Study; interim report, November 26, 1990; list of potential participants in Quick Response project; newspaper clippings, handwritten notes
- Kurt Salmon Associates (KSA): Quick Response Project (2 folders), 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
  Proposal outline draft, August 30, 1991; primary notes from the focus group, June 26,1991, with cover letter to GIDC president Bruce Herman; draft, Succeeding in Apparel in the Nineties, by KSA, June 1991; report, "GIDC: Keeping New York in Fashion," by KSA, August 18, 1992; "Saks/After Five Quick Response Demonstration Project," by KSA, April 1992; draft, "Saks/Carole Hochman Quick Response Demonstration Project," by KSA, May 1992; press releases, KSA newsletters, and other printed publicity materials; handwritten notes, newspaper clippings
- Board of Directors, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  Board of Directors meeting minutes, March 28 and June 13; memo to ILGWU president Mazur from GIDC president Adam Friedman, "Program Status Report," summarizing activities of first three quarters of fiscal year, April 2, 1990; Application to the New York State Department of Economic Development Regional Economic Development Partnership Program, submitted by the Garment Industry Development Corporation, July 6, 1990, with cover note to ILGWU exec. asst. James Parrott; supporting materials re nomination of GIDC for U.S. Dept. of Labor "LIFT" outstanding training award, including history and achievements of GIDC and overview of garment industry in NY; newspaper clippings; letters and telegrams from ILGWU president Mazur to NYS Senate and Assembly leaders re restoring funding to Employer Specific Skills Training Grant (ESSTG) program, related correspondence; Marketing and Technology Study Interim Report re needs of NYC manufacturers, by Kurt Salmon Associates; Discussion Outline for GIDC covering the Strategic Planning Study by Kurt Salmon Associates; application to NYS Regional Economic Development Partnership Program for Employer Needs Project; memos to Mazur re GIDC budget cuts
- Annual Report, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  Annual Report, 1989-90; list of board members, 1990-91; press release re marketing study commissioned with Kurt Salmon Associates, Sept. 10, 1990; correspondence between ILG president Mazur, coat manufacturer Fairbrooke Enterprises, and Vince Tese, NYS Commissioner of Economic Development re grant to train employees on new state-of-the-art equipment that had been sitting idle for lack of skilled operators, August 1990; letter from, Mazur to U.S. Secretary of Labor supporting GIDC proposal for grant for bilingual vocational training to upgrade skills of dislocated garment workers, Aug. 29, 1990; GIDC budget and salary recommendations to the board of directors, June 5, 1990
- Board of Directors, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  January-February Activity Report; 1991; "Summary of Accomplishments During 1989-90 Program Year"; memo to ILG president Mazur re GIDC accomplishments, 8/21/90; statement to auditors signed by GIDC president Bruce Herman and treasurer Jay Mazur, Aug. 31, 1990; auditor's report, June 30, 1990; financial records (revenue sources); correspondence with consultants Kurt Salmon Associates; handwritten notes from board meeting, 12/12/90; correspondence with speaker of the NYS Assembly re budget cut, Jan. 28, 1991; from Regional Education Center for Economic Development, thanking Mazur for successful lobbying effort to restore funding, Jan. 14, 1991; memo to Mazur from Bruce Herman re invitation from Australian Manufacturing Council (attached) for trip, and proposed trip to Hong Kong to examine competition, March 15, 1991; press release by Hong Kong Trade Development Council re 1991 Fashion Week; edited press release re appointment of Bruce Herman as president of GIDC, Jan. 31, 1991; profile of GIDC president Bruce Herman in Crain's New York Business, Mar. 1, 1991; correspondence with applicants for president of GIDC, attached list of applicants; child care survey (English and Spanish); edited copy for newsletter, Nov. 9, 1990; memo to Mazur's exec. asst. re state audit of old Super Sewer's program, requesting intervention with Dept. of Labor to avert "tremendous waste of both our resources" and "nightmare" review of eligibility issues, Nov. 19, 1990; positive evaluation of Super Sewers program by NYC Dept. of Employment
- Board of Directors, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  Mar.-Apr. activity report; report on NY area garment industry: Interim Review of Findings, Analyses, Recommendations of Strategy Planning for GIDC, by Kurt Salmon Associates; data on children's wear firms; memos re training for ex-Domsey (Brooklyn) workers, alternative funding sources to federal grants due to ineligibility of undocumented immigrants; report on problems with training program: lack of cooperation by employer partner/grant recipient Metropolitan Fashion Center (MFC; see also separate heading) in hiring trained graduates, need for ILGWU to assist in placement in decent jobs to restore integrity of program; letters from Mazur to department stores Macy's, Bloomingdale's, Alexander's, re meeting with GIDC to discuss market trends; statistical analysis of child care survey of ILGWU garment workers; profile of GIDC president Bruce Herman in Crain's New York Business, Mar. 1, 1991
- Board of Directors, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  July-Sept. Board of Directors meeting agenda and handwritten notes, 7/25; minutes, 4/17; memo to Executive Committee re FY92 budget and salary recommendations, GIDC budget, 1991-92; memo re ILGWU contributions for FY91 and 92 by local; letters to local managers from ILGWU president Mazur soliciting contributions; correspondence re personnel issues; job description for job development consultant; invoices for equipment; memos re union benefits policies as impediments to training recruitment, employer evasion of unemployment insurance payments and impact on worker retraining eligibility under federal guidelines
- Board of Directors: Exports, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  Agenda, Fashion Exports New York, 7/1; project budget; computer printout, U.S. Export Markets by country of destination and apparel category, 1987-91; newspaper clippings
- Board of Directors, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  Oct.-Dec. Board of Directors meeting agenda, 11/19; minutes, 7/25; Sept.-Oct. activity report; GIDC FY92 budget; A Child Care Study of the Garment Industry executive summary and newspaper clippings; project proposal and list of advisory committee members for Women's Apparel Quick Response Supplier Network to develop faster production turnaround capabilities for high-value product; Fashion Exports New York brochure; printed article re lack of government support for NY garment industry by ILGWU president Jay Mazur in Crain's New York Business
- Board of Directors, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  Jan.-Mar. Activity reports re training program, child care; Small Business Advisory Board member list and mission statement; conference program, "Moving Toward a Safer and More Productive Workplace," proposal to the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation by the Urban Research Center of the Wagner Graduate School of Public Service (NYU) for feasibility study on reviving specialized manufacturing in the outer boroughs, request from program officer to GIDC for evaluation; letters from NYS Dept. of Economic Development re grant approvals for GIDC and Metropolitan Fashion Center of Greater NY (MFC); proposal for Expo Tech 92, educational event re computer automation for small business, by Manhattan Development Corp.; audit of GIDC 1990-91 financial statement; draft of Kurt Salmon Associates' marketing and technology assessment of NY women and children's apparel industry; initial planning meeting agenda for project of Clark Foundation, "How Can We Get NY Working Again? Employment Strategies for New York City" with note from GIDC president Bruce Herman to ILGWU exec. Asst. James Parrott; handwritten notes of meetings; newspaper clippings
- Board of Directors: Forum, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  Jan.-Mar. Keeping NY in Fashion forum: list of participants, executive summary, draft and final script of speech by ILGWU president Jay Mazur, letter from NYS Office of the Governor inviting Mazur to speak; press release, newspaper clippings; copy of photo of Bob Frazier, Kurt Salmon Associates (original in Kheel photo archives); photocopies of slide presentation re garment industry
- Board of Directors, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  Apr.-June Board of Directors meeting agenda, 6/30/92; minutes, 11/19/91; FY92-93 salary recommendations; correspondence with Consortium for Worker Education re contract for vocational training for dislocated sewing machine operators, ESL instruction; course evaluation survey results; lists of training programs, 1991-92; correspondence with Mazur re promotion of exports; budgets
- Board of Directors, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  July-Sept. July-August activity report; draft of agreement between GIDC and Kurt Salmon Associates (KSA) to develop Quick Response Supplier Network demonstration projects to improve garment manufacturing turnaround time; KSA consulting rate sheet; letter from KSA reporting poor response from high-end department stores and manufacturers; letters from ILG president Mazur to locals, requesting contributions to GIDC; discussion of RFP from Con Edison to implement energy efficient technologies; description of project manager position, letters of application, recommendation for hire; memo re skills training programs; memo re exhibit at annual Bobbin Show; 1992-93 budget amendment
- G. Metropolitan Fashion Center (Box 17, Folder 15a)
- Metropolitan Fashion Center, 1990-1992 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  Proposed production facility at the Brooklyn Army Terminal serving Chinatown manufacturers, financed by a grant from the State of New York, with training of factory workers provided by GIDC. Letter from NYS Department of Economic Development Commissioner Vince Tese to Metropolitan Fashion Center, notifying of award of grant, Mar. 27, 1992; description of center; report, "A Day Care Center in the Brooklyn Army Terminal: A Needs Assessment: Current and Potential Demand," prepared by the ILGWU with the cooperation of the Public Development Corporation, Dec. 6, 1990; letter from NYC mayor David Dinkins to ILG president Mazur thanking him for doing the needs assessment for a pilot day care center; memo from ILG vice president Susan Cowell to Mazur re ILG support for day care center as an economic development issue, Feb. 6, 1991; draft marketing proposal by ILG exec. asst. James Parrott, with cover letter, Jan. 4, 1991; update, Feb. 15, 1991; hand-edited draft of letter/request for proposals for consultant to develop marketing plan; Request for Proposals for Women's and Children's Apparel Marketing and Technology Study; ILG memos expressing frustration with MFC for not putting up its share of funds for the marketing project, concern that further delay will damage credibility of ILG and GIDC, Aug. 1991; correspondence between MFC principals Sherman Ng and Edison Wong and ILG exec. asst. James Parrott, NYS director of Industrial Effectiveness Programs, and others, re MFC's cash flow projections, shifting commitment to the project, 1990-91; press releases from MFC and equipment maker Juki Corporation, 1990; newspaper clippings, handwritten notes
- Metropolitan Fashion Center (MFC): Marketing Proposals (2 Folders), 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 17-18)
  Responses to Request for Proposals by: Emanuel Weintraub Associates (with handwritten notes of meeting, Mar. 14, 1991); Deloitte & Touche, 1990; KPMG Peat Marwick, "Market Plan for Recapturing the Competitive Edge in Apparel Manufacturing," Mar. 8, 1991; handwritten notes comparing proposals, Mar. 91
- Metropolitan Fashion Center (MFC): Marketing Study, Kurt Salmon Associates, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  Correspondence from Kurt Salmon Associates; revised project plan; notes of meetings with detailed internal issues discussion, final report, May 7, 1992; projected levels of employment
- H. Management Consultants: Emanuel Weintraub (Box 17, Folder 19a)
- Management Consultants: Emanuel Weintraub, 1989-1992 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  Proposals and reports by management consultant on marketing, flexible manufacturing systems; seminar materials on competitiveness; article reprints, authored by Weintraub, from Bobbin; newsletters, The Weintraub Report; correspondence with ILGWU exec asst James Parrott; handwritten notes
- Management Consultants: Emanuel Weintraub, 1989-1992 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- I. Fashion Exports/New York (FE/NY) (Box 18, Folder 1a)
- Fashion Exports/New York (FE/NY), 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  A cooperative project of the Garment Industry Development Corporation (GIDC) and the Council for American Fashion (CAF). Letter from NYS Department of Economic Development commissioner Vince Tese to the Garment Industry Development Corp. (GIDC), notifying them of a grant award to develop an Export Trade Development Project, January 10, 1991; overview of FE/NY's mission, May 28, 1992; letters of application for resource coordinator; memos discussing sending FE/NY director/program coordinator Leah Kaplan to European trade show Igedo, outline of plans, and letters of support; project budget; typed notes on meetings/conversations, 1/22/91 and 1/24/91; Export Success Stories, August 13, 1992, re Maidenform and Andmore; drafts of brochure; printed brochures: "Canada First!" "Selling to Latin America," and "Fashion Exports New York"; descriptive text, with hand editing, for overseas brochure re Fashion Exports/New York, with cover letter requesting comments, Aug. 7, 1992; description of Request for Proposals for GIDC Export Grant Application, Sept. 10, 1992; correspondence between FE/NY's Kaplan and CAF re meetings with local firms, Russian and other international companies interested in exports, Japan Apparel Initiative (see also Japan, Kobe Mart); letters of support from firms and NYC government for grant renewal; advisory notices to ILGWU local managers re export assistance given to firms in their jurisdictions; newspaper clippings, handwritten notes
- FE/NY Budget, 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  "Notes on FE/NY Spending"; CAF Budget Check, 11/6/91; memo, "Export Contract Extension Request," Apr. 23, 1992; CAF Finance Report: Report to Steering Committee, Mar. 23, 1991
- FE/NY Client Companies, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  Lists of companies receiving assistance from FE/NY export program; general mailing list; correspondence
- FE/NY Financial Reports (4 folders) (Box 18, Folder 5-8)
  Quarterly reports to the New York State Department of Economic Development
- FE/NY Invoices, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  Copies of invoices and checks written by the ILGWU or GIDC for Japan export trade show and other joint export projects with the Council for American Fashion (CAF), the Fashion Institute of Technology (FIT), and Fashion Exports/New York
- American Apparel Manufacturers Association (Export Promotion), 1991 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  Handwritten list of members; list of ILG firms belonging to AAMA, 12/19/91; memo from Council for American Fashion expressing eagerness of CAF, GIDC, and FIT to participate in an event similar to the Au Printemps promotion (copy of article attached)
- Consultants, 1989-1992 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  List of export experts used in Fashion Institute of Technology (FIT) seminars in 1990; correspondence and materials from export consultants APCO Associates, Assist International, Hedy Wilder Associates, Coopers & Lybrand, and Redwood Associates/Irving Vigdor; plan for export expansion seminars cosponsored by KPMG Peat Marwick, the U.S. Dept. of Commerce Office of Textiles and Apparel, and Irving Vigdor; copy of slide presentation on the European Commission; handwritten notes; brochures
- Export Assistance: Federal Government, 1988-1992 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  Announcement by the U.S. Dept. of Commerce of the establishment of the Consortia of American Businesses in the Newly Independent States (CABNIS) grant program for companies interested in exporting to the former Soviet Union and aiding in its privatization, July 13, 1992; Small Business Administration fact sheets, export workshop calendar, publications; newspaper clippings
- New Jersey Institute of Technology, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  Announcement by the U.S. Dept. of Commerce of the establishment of the Consortia of American Businesses in the Newly Independent States (CABNIS) grant program for companies interested in exporting to the former Soviet Union and aiding in its privatization, July 13, 1992; letter from the Council for American Fashion to the New Jersey Institute of Technology endorsing its application for CABNIS grant, August 21, 1992; handwritten notes
- NYC, 1990-1992 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  Letter from ILG president Mazur to NYC mayor Dinkins requesting meeting to plan promotion of exports to Japan, December 12, 1990; letter from GIDC/ILGWU to NYC deputy assistant commissioner requesting additional grant money for Fashion Exports/New York for FY 1992-93; confidential letter from ILG president Mazur to NYC deputy mayor requesting additional grant money, noting state aid will run out; descriptive summary of Pilot International Matchmaking Program, a project of the NYC Office of International Trade & Investment (Department of Ports & Trade) with the European Cooperation Network; correspondence between Office of International Trade & Investment and Council for American Fashion re working together, May 7, 1990; draft text of brochure to promote NYC manufacturing facilities to foreign designers; description of Motexha international trade fair held in Dubai, United Arab Emerites, 1990; newspaper clippings
- NYC: Brooklyn Goes Global, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  A project of Brooklynworks, a coalition of industry, academic, and labor institutions. Program description; description of proposed global fashion show; letter from Garment Industry Development Corp. (GIDC) to ILG officials expressing reservations about show as promoting fragmentation of industry, but interest in telemarketing aspect, March 30, 1993
- NYC: Holtzman Report, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  Study by New York City comptroller Elizabeth Holtzman re possible public initiatives to promote exporting, with summary press release
- New York State, 1990-1993 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  Letter from NYS Dept. of Economic Development commissioner Vince Tese to Garment Industry Development Corp. (GIDC) that grant has been approved under the Global Market Export Service (GEMS), Feb. 2, 1993; letter from Council for American Fashion (CAF) to NYS Dept. of Economic Development suggesting revising GEMS grant eligibility to reflect how NYC garment industry is organized (jobber/contractor distinction), August 4, 1993; announcement from NYS Dept. of Economic Development re availability of export assistance grants to small businesses and nonprofits, August 15, 1991, with application form; letter from the executive director of the Port Authority of NY & NJ to ILG president Mazur discussing closer collaboration with the Garment Industry Development Corp. (GIDC), Sept. 19, 1990; memo from FE/NY coordinator to GIDC proposing areas of collaboration with Port Authority, July 12, 1993; brochures for NYS Global Export Market Service (GEMS); for World Trade Center Network; bulletin from NYS Dept. of Economic Development, "Export Opportunities for New York State Businesses"; flyer from NYS Dept. of Economic Development, "Export to Europe Now"; description of Eximbank Working Capital Loan Guarantee Program, Port Authority of NY & NJ; brochure, "Bringing New Products to the World's Great Marketplaces," by XPORT, the Port Authority's export trading company
- Nonapparel Industries, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 18)
- Statistics, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 19)
- J. FE/NY: Country Markets and Trade Shows (Box 18, Folder 19a)
- Canada, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  Brochure, "Canada First! Textiles/Apparel Seminar," March 18-19, 1991; press release from accountants KPMG Peat Marwick, "'Canada First' Program Offers Apparel and Textile Companies Business Strategies for Canadian Market," September 3, 1991; newspaper clippings
- Europe, 1990-1992 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  "Trade Opportunities: Europe," summary sheet by Fashion Exports/New York; list of international trade shows; memo re Premier trade show in England; list of European buyer groups for apparel and letter sent to them from FE/NY offering free services, April 20, 1992; breakfast meetings sponsored by FE/NY about exporting opportunities to Europe (Igedo trade show); list of apparel and textile export trade shows around the world through October 1992, by U.S. Dept. of Commerce; the Euro-American Club's Bulletin, Sept./Oct. 1991; announcement by the U.S. Dept. of Commerce of the establishment of the Consortia of American Businesses in the Newly Independent States (CABNIS) grant program for companies interested in exporting to the former Soviet Union and aiding in its privatization, July 13, 1992; letter to ILGWU from Scott Tag & Label, re need for conversion to metric system; newspaper clippings on trade fairs, including pullout of ACTWU and Clothing Manufacturer's Association from SEHM show in Paris; handwritten notes
- Europe: Igedo Trade Show, 1991-1994 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  Announcements/information packets for annual Igedo Dusseldorf (Germany); memos from Council for American Fashion; list, "FE/NY Firms Potentially Interested in IGEDO"; list of U.S. exhibitors, 1991, with question as to whether any are ILGWU firms; newspaper clippings
- Europe: Igedo Trade Show Preparations and Follow-up, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  Memos from CAF re funding and letters of support for FE/NY coordinator Leah Kaplan to attend; letters from Kaplan to firms preparing to attend; post-conference briefing memos to firms re contacts made, interest expressed by German buyers
- Europe: Germany, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  Report by the Roche Group under contract to Kormos, Harris & Associates for Industry, Science and Technology Canada, "European Market Entry Planning: West Germany"; overview of market outlook; Business Week article, "Think Small"
- Europe: Netherlands, 1991-1993 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  Apparel market study for the Netherlands, Aug. 1989; correspondence
- Hong Kong, 1990-1992 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  "Hong Kong's Market for Apparel and Clothing Accessories"; "Industry and Product Profile: Hong Kong's Clothing Industry", 1991; visitor arrival statistics, 1991; correspondence between Garment Industry Development Corp. and Council for American Fashion re first trade mission of Hong Kong buyers to the U.S., expressing concern over whether intent of delegation is to "knock off" New York designers for local producers; faxed notice to ILGWU local managers re status of buyers' mission, noting concern over intent, Oct. 7, 1992; briefing itinerary at U.S. Dept. of Commerce office in NY; speech delivered to the Asia Society in New York by Kazuo Wada, chairman, Yaohan Department Store Company, "Yaohan's International Strategy," April 23, 1990, re why store is relocating to Hong Kong, with note from GIDC to CAF; press release from the Hong Kong Trade Development Council re Hong Kong Fashion Week 1991; press release from the Italian Trade Commission re participation in Hong Kong Fashion Week 1991; letter to Garment Industry Development Corp. from Hong Kong Trade Development Council confirming exhibit space at Hong Kong Fashion Week 1992, noting past participants from Italy and Japan